<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Selfhelp on Jason Kuehl Blog</title><link>https://blog.jasonkuehl.com/tags/selfhelp/</link><description>Recent content in Selfhelp on Jason Kuehl Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jasonkuehl.com/tags/selfhelp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From Engineer to Manager</title><link>https://blog.jasonkuehl.com/p/from-engineer-to-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jasonkuehl.com/p/from-engineer-to-manager/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.jasonkuehl.com/p/from-engineer-to-manager/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post From Engineer to Manager" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="being-awesome"&gt;Being awesome
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As someone who initially hesitated to take on a management role, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned some valuable lessons that I’d like to share. If you’re contemplating a similar path, you may be facing similar feelings of uncertainty. One key thing to understand is that, regardless of your new title, you will always carry your identity as an engineer. Transitioning into management doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean abandoning your engineering skills; rather, it involves using them in a different capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of being directly involved in the hands-on aspects of projects, you will become the strategic architect behind them. Your role will shift to overseeing the planning and organization of projects, ensuring that every detail is considered and executed efficiently. You will start to focus on developing project timelines, allocating resources, and managing budgets, all while maintaining the technical standards you’ve cultivated throughout your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, a crucial part of your new responsibilities will be guiding and mentoring your team. You’ll play a pivotal role in fostering an environment that encourages professional growth among your employees. This involves conducting training sessions, providing constructive feedback, and empowering your team to enhance their engineering skills. By taking on this supportive role, you&amp;rsquo;ll not only help them improve but also elevate the quality of work produced by your entire team. The journey may be challenging, but embracing your management position can lead to fulfilling new opportunities both for yourself and your colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an engineer, your success was defined by my ability to solve problems, write Terraform, and deliver new infrastructure. However, transitioning to a managerial role brought about a significant shift in focus. It was no longer about yout individual contributions; it was about enabling the success of the team. This shift required me to let go of direct technical contributions and embrace the role of a facilitator and mentor. Learning to trust my team, delegate effectively, and measure success by their growth, cohesion, and impact became crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing people presents a unique set of challenges. Unlike Terraform, which is logical and predictable, people are complex. Understanding the individual motivations of team members, resolving conflicts, and balancing camaraderie with accountability are all essential skills. This understanding not only helps in managing the team effectively but also fosters a sense of empathy and connection with team members, which is vital in a managerial role.
I also had to broaden my perspective, thinking long-term, aligning team goals with the business vision, and advocating for the team in conversations with senior leadership. This required learning to “manage up” while maintaining a balance between empowering my team and meeting organizational objectives.
The most significant lesson I&amp;rsquo;ve learned is that management is not just a career change; it’s a shift in mindset. It’s about transitioning from being a problem-solver to an enabler, and from focusing solely on technical excellence to nurturing people and culture. While I still value technical proficiency, the true joy now comes from witnessing my team succeed, grow, and collectively make a significant impact. This sense of fulfillment—from seeing the seeds of my guidance blossom into success—is a testament to the success of my transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This journey wont been without its challenges, but it will been gratifying. It’s a continuous process of learning and introspection—a reminder that, as managers, our most significant success lies in the success of the people we lead. This emphasis on continuous learning and reflection underscores the need for constant improvement and growth in the management role, making it a vital part of our professional journey. It&amp;rsquo;s a journey that keeps us engaged, reflective, and always striving for better.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Startups from the Significant Others' Perspective</title><link>https://blog.jasonkuehl.com/p/startups-from-the-significant-others-perspective/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jasonkuehl.com/p/startups-from-the-significant-others-perspective/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.jasonkuehl.com/p/startups-from-the-significant-others-perspective/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Startups from the Significant Others' Perspective" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Startups from the Significant Others&amp;rsquo; Perspective&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have spent many years working in startups before transitioning to a more corporate role. Before diving into the details, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss the three phases of every startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phase 1: The Jank - Startups begin with a quickly and informally developed idea, often with minimal documented processes, but it either works or is close to an end product. These are the essential people during this early stage of building the business. They focus on rapid execution to meet crucial deadlines vital for survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phase 2: This phase marks the shift from informal methods to a formalized process, involving automation, documentation, and initiating thorough design reviews to enhance the product. The &amp;ldquo;Get Stuff Done&amp;rdquo; individual now operates within new boundaries and begins building automation. Typically, personnel change at this stage, with new team members taking over. The focus remains on “we need this to make money,&amp;quot; but now includes developing timelines, managing customer expectations, and understanding the time required for development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phase 3: This final stage can take years to achieve, involving a documented, process-oriented, and PMO-enforced workforce. Timelines are respected, processes are created where lacking, and there’s no need to say “To build this or we don&amp;rsquo;t have jobs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many startups try to skip steps or rush through processes, believing they don&amp;rsquo;t need a structured approach and thinking they can &amp;ldquo;make it go faster.&amp;rdquo; However, most startups face a significant ramp-up period, just like any other company, and simply throwing people at the problem isn&amp;rsquo;t effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Startups should focus on teams developing revenue-generating products. Employees want the
company to grow, not to face job cuts. So, why is there such intense pressure on the product team? When shortcuts are taken and there&amp;rsquo;s an effort to do more with less, senior management notices the increased productivity. They often see this as a way to increase profits from the final product. When you ask for more, they show how much has been accomplished with fewer resources. You won&amp;rsquo;t get more until real failures happen, unless the workplace is toxic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High employee turnover, Lack of career growth, Lack of appreciation,poor communication, and a lack of work-life balance—coupled with removing positions without backfills—create the impression that the issue lies with the individual rather than the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that sounded like your significant other or friends casually talking about their day at work, it might be because you work somewhere that can be tough on employees, pushing them to succeed at any cost. About 55 percent of reasons why people leave a company are poor management, work-life balance issues, leadership problems, and toxic culture, while pay accounts for only 15%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings me to the end. Why do startups fail or face long-term issues? Poor leadership and management are often the causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phases I mentioned earlier are guided by management, not by individual contributors or those actively involved in the product. Failure is never the fault of a single person or team; instead, it results from flawed processes or the lack of proper procedures. Leaders and managers must understand this. Punishing employees and disregarding their feedback only makes matters worse. They are actually trying to highlight issues and propose improvements. As a leader, it is your responsibility to listen carefully and respond appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a responsibility to share your information with your team to support their growth, development, and ensure everyone has what they need to succeed. Avoid threats like “Well, if we don&amp;rsquo;t get this, it&amp;rsquo;s the end” or dismissive remarks like “We&amp;rsquo;ll make it work,” as these can cause you to lose the respect of your colleagues. Recognize who your stars are and do not penalize those who are genuinely trying to achieve more with less.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Learn By Failing</title><link>https://blog.jasonkuehl.com/p/failing-is-learning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jasonkuehl.com/p/failing-is-learning/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.jasonkuehl.com/p/failing-is-learning/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Learn By Failing" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="learn-by-failing"&gt;Learn By Failing
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It happened. You finally landed that next large project, the one that you think will defend all of your decisions leading up to this point. The big one that will redeem all of that hard work during the years leading up to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the fact is that there is no one project that will do that. No one project will ever do that because that’s not how life works. All these projects really are is a way to gain more experience and learn from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately and despite the actually reality of the situation, there are many people out there that still believe that one large project will make or break their career. And this causes lots of distress and lots of negative self-talk. This is especially true for people working in a start-up and in enterprise business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows are sayings (that negative self-talk) that I have heard from many people in my life. I’m going to write about each and give you ways to help better yourself and give you the confidence you need to succeed. While I am no expert, I hope that this can help at least a few people realize that failure is part of life and one project will not make or break you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="if-i-fail-im-going-to-be-fired"&gt;If I fail, I’m going to be fired.
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I see this a lot especially with new people (Interns, Jrs, and fresh engineers). That being said, I have also seen this with Seniors, but I’ll cover that case as well later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re fresh to the tech world, and you feel that this statement is true where you are, you need to create a workplace that allows you to fail. You need a space that gives you people to learn from and someone to lean on when (yes not “if” but “when”) you do fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you’re new, so of course, you’re afraid to do a lot of things; you need someone to ask, “Hey, I’m going to do X. Is that ok?” This is very important for all teams to have great communication. Be it quick, useful meetings, chat rooms, emails, or all of the above, you need to find a place that everyone talks to each other and helps each other through potential failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your company is not supportive like this, you need to move on. Nobody needs that negativity in their life. You should never be afraid to fail and your workplace should reflect an attitude of failure is how people learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="if-something-fails-then-clearly-someone-is-to-blame"&gt;If something fails then clearly someone is to blame
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tim broke X or Todd did Y. in reality, rarely are Tim and Todd the issue here. The process is. 99 times out of a 100 something failed because the process wasn’t well defined or was incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every place you go should have run books or SOPs or some sort of documentation on how a process should be done. If that process is followed and something fails, it is the process that didn’t work, and it needs to be updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about the new process or undocumented items you might ask? Then it’s time to build a process and implement it. Before implementing it though, you have to make sure to thoroughly test it and make sure it works. This way others will have one for next time. And then you document it so clearly that anyone could follow it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst case scenario of this is when only 1 person knows the process. A process that is in some guy’s head is not a process, that’s a failure point. When Tim needs help with X, but Jenny is on vacation, and you can’t fix X, that’s a problem and it’s nobody’s fault but the company for not having standard written processes. Get all processes on paper to prevent failure like this and remember it’s not your fault if your company hasn’t written processes down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you fail, you’re weak and not good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imposter syndrome is genuine. It doesn’t matter if you’re new to the field or have been doing this for years. You get this feeling that you are somehow inferior because you failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you bust that feeling? Well, everyone has something that helps, but surrounding yourself with a network of people to build you up and remind you that failure just means you are learning is very important. If you don’t have that network of people, you feel like you’re lost at sea with no land around you. You need to build that support structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="denial-of-mistake-making"&gt;Denial of Mistake Making
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem with people and companies is is denying when you have made a mistake, or a project didn’t go as planned. I’ve seen many a ship sink on this iceberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a hard thing to teach people because most people (especially Americans) have been programmed to think that failure is never an option and that failure will lead to my first point (being fired).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, you need to fail to learn so that your project can go on. No project ever works the first time. I mean think of the greatest scientific achievements in history: all of them came about through trial and error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, fear of failure is so engrained into our society that it is very hard to break people of that mindset. There is no cookbook that helps people understand this. It takes working in a positive work environment to reassure you that failing is just part of the process. It’s with that reassurance that you can build up your confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Who is Causing These Issues and Feelings to Occur?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the most part people’s outlook of the workplace is influenced by what is around them. So, besides societal pressure to never fail, who is perpetuating this false claim that failure is the worst thing ever and that you will be fired and branded a loser if you fail?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toxic people: They have one goal, suck your life away. They don’t care about you and will only bring you misery. They only care about themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-to-id-these-kinds-of-people"&gt;How to ID these kinds of people?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re emotionally affected by their drama.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You dread (or fear) being around them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re exhausted, or you feel angry while you’re with them or after your interaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You feel bad or ashamed about yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re stuck in a cycle of trying to rescue, fix, or care for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sooner you remove them from your life, the sooner you can work on building up your confidence again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="toxic-space"&gt;Toxic Space
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you see these run, don’t look back, and move on. Always remember that you can leave at any time, you don’t owe any company anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to ID these kinds of places?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re told to feel, “lucky you have a job.”…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poor communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone has a bad attitude. …&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s always office drama. …&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dysfunction reigns. …&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have a tyrannical boss. …&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You feel in your gut that something is off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power of “no” is amazing, and you shouldn’t be afraid to use it. You have a choice, and you know better than all that your priorities are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="poor-leaders"&gt;Poor Leaders
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like toxic people, these are the people who will help drive your future in your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oppositional behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Makes you feel terrible for over simple mistake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plays power politics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn’t tech or let you learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abuse of the disciplinary system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bullying, gaslighting, sexists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;course causes workplace division&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-should-your-leadership-actually-be-doing"&gt;What should your leadership actually be doing?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seeing a potential vision on your future, asking what you want your future to be, and helping to shape it to meet both of your needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving you an ability to drive your own projects you thought of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports you when you need it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being there for you when you need someone to talk to or toss ideas off of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can tell them no and have a talk about why you said no.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-can-you-do-right-now"&gt;What Can You Do Right Now
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve talked about what failure types and people who are not supportive and ways to identify them. But what can you do to build your empire and get that reinforcement if it’s not in the workplace and find a place where it is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a network. : Go out and meet others in your field and talk shop. You will figure out you’re not alone and that others might have similar issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to fun events: Go to events that look like fun to meet others and build upon that network. Even if that’s something you never done before. Build your community or join one with positive people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start doing fun in field projects: If you really like the work you are doing, start practicing outside of work! To be good at something, it needs to be close to second nature. Start doing in-field projects outside of work or if your work has a “playpen” where you can build and make things use it. Check the areas for a local makerspace, too, as these are great places to find others with your passions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work and people can be a chore in and of itself. It can trigger anxiety, stress, and feeling of dread some (if not most) days. You need your time to decompress. Maybe that is time with your significant other, playing at a makerspace, out with friends, building a car, writing, drawing, video games; whatever it might be, think about yourself and what you like to do. Whatever your life stress is, think about yourself. Your health is worth more than ending up in the ER because of a panic attack (True Story).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I talking about all this? Why does this even need to be informed about? People think “failure is a sin” is normal, and it’s not. If you’re reading this is going, “Wow, I see this at work” or “wow, this is happening to me now” it’s because this happens daily to a lot of people. It’s not until you identify what happening that you can work on the way to resolve it. Unfortunately, some companies and people are so set in their ways that it can feel like moving a Stubborn mule to get any real change to happen. They’re not going to change, and these kinds of people don’t want too. You have a choice and a voice to do what you want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t let others think they can control you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>